# **NGUYEN THANH LONG**

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### **CONTACT**

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

With over 2 years of experience working with Hardware and Networking, I have good knowledge of information systems, data communication, networking, and quick learning skills. With the desire for more challenges and knowledge, now I am working as a software developer. My goal is to be a full-stack web developer in the next 2-3 years.

### **KEY SKILLS**

Front-end: HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | Reactjs | Redux | Tailwind CSS | SASS

Back-end: Nodejs | Expressjs | MongoDB Database | Realtime Database Firebase

Others: Git | Github | RESTful APIs | JSON | JWT

Soft skills: Independent | Coordinated | Adaptive | Responsible | Funny | Honest | Sociable

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Learning Web Development**

(05/2022 - Present)

- Proficiency in front-end development HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6)
- Familiarity with CSS frameworks: Tailwind CSS/Materials and CSS preprocessor: SASS/SCSS
- Understanding React frameworks and its core principles
- Experience with popular ReactJS workflow: Redux
- Knowledge of source code management tool: Git
- Understanding RESTful APIs, JSON, Node (ExpressJS), NoSQL (MongoDB)

## **Viettel Group – Viettel Business Solution Corporation** (08/2021 – 05/2022)

#### IT Solutions Consultant

- Respond to pre-sales activities such as receiving customer requests, consulting, solution design/product instruction and quantity/cost estimation.
- Respond to after-sales activities such as project implementation, solving technical problems and capturing customer feedback.
- The point of contact (customers, partners) for IT projects under Viettel's services such as surveillance cameras, automatic metering infrastructure, video conferencing, etc. in the assigned area.

### Viettel Group – Viettel Ho Chi Minh City Branch (07/2019 – 07/2021)

### IT Support Tecnician

• Troubleshoot arising problems such as computer systems, network systems, office software, projector, printer, wifi, scanner...

- Install computers for new employees and implement new systems (hardware/software) as required based on technical requirements
- Responsible for building and managing network systems, cameras at the office and branches
- Build technical documents, user documents for customers.

# ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

Vietnam National University HCMC International University Bachelor of Electrical Engineering - *Graduated 2018* 

## PERSONAL INTERESTS

Coffee | Gym | Football | Tennis | Technical | Development | Coding

## **PROJECTS**

## 1. Shop-node app

Descriptions	An SSR application allows users to manage and buy products
Features	<ul> <li>Create, modify, and delete products that the users post to the app</li> <li>Validate email/password and authenticate the user when login or signup</li> <li>Validate product information when the user posts to ap or modifies the available product in the app</li> <li>Handle forget password and reset password when users forget</li> <li>Store the information login user/products in MongoDB Database</li> <li>Add products to the cart and order products from the cart</li> </ul>
Technology in use	Express, MongoDB database, Mongoose library, EJS Template Engine, Nodemailer package, Sendgrid cloud email service
Link demo	https://shop-node-app.onrender.com/

# 2. Order-food app

Descriptions	A web application to order meals.
Features	<ul> <li>Display available a meal list</li> <li>Choose the quantity of each meal, add meals to the cart</li> <li>Review added meals and the total price in the cart</li> <li>Validating the information of the user and sending the order to the Firebase database</li> </ul>
Technology in use	ReactJS, Redux Toolkit, Realtime Database Firebase
Link demo	https://foodmeals-longnguyen.netlify.app

## 3. Recipe app

Descriptions	A web application helps the customer find the food recipe, customizing the recipe
	according to the number of people served.

Features	<ul> <li>Search for the meal and display a meal list depending on the name</li> <li>Customize the number of serving persons, re-update recipe ingredients</li> <li>Bookmark the recipe</li> <li>Add the custom recipe to the bookmark</li> </ul>
Technology in use	HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript ES6
Link demo	https://recipe-longnguyen.netlify.app